我爸寄来了个包裹
We got a package from my dad.
盒子上没有气孔
No air holes in the box.
这是个好兆头
That's a good sign.
莉莉很喜欢那只小鸡
Lily loved having that chicken.
后来吃得也很开心  尽管她不知情
One more time than she realized.
我刚收到婚礼歌手的电邮
Listen, I just got an e-mail from our wedding singer.
-他有个小要求  -又来吗
- He has a small request.   - Another one?
婚礼歌手何时开始向我们提要求了
Since when does the wedding singer send us requests?
不  他只是想把你的几首歌换掉
Well, no, he just wants to change a few songs in your medley
以免跟他要表演的部分重复
to avoid overlap with the stuff that he's performing.
可别换了我的重头戏
Well, I hope it's none of my showstoppers.
你的歌都是重头戏啦
Oh, they're all showstoppers.
你太好了
Oh, you're too kind.
天啊  是我们
Oh, my gosh, it's us.
放在我们的婚礼蛋糕上
For our wedding cake.
是不是激动得要死了
Couldn't you just die?
我真觉得我要死了
I really think I could.
我爸爸做的
My dad made this.
他可是世界级的肥皂雕刻师
He's a world-class soap carver.
我小时候有一次说脏话
You know, once, when I was a kid, I cussed,
我妈妈用他雕的比萨斜塔
and my mom washed my mouth out
洗我的嘴
with the leaning tower of Pisa.
她到现在还在自责
She still blames herself to this day.
本来我是会马上反对那个婚礼蛋糕人偶的
Oh, I would have nixed that wedding topper immediately,
但小卡跟我有项协议
but Cam and I have an agreement.
我们每人有三次否决对方婚礼创意的机会
We -- we each got three vetoes of each other's wedding ideas --
无需任何理由
No questions asked.
倒是  实施了那么一小会儿
And it -- it worked for...a while
你会爱上我的婚礼公告牌的
I think you're gonna love my wedding board.
我也非常激动
I'm pretty excited, too.
-反对  -反对
- Veto.   - Veto.
- Veto.  - Veto.
很抱歉我太激动了
I'm sorry I'm so emotional.
真的是最棒的礼物了
It's just the nicest thing ever.
你不觉得我看起来有点
You don't think that I look just a little bit --
我爸爸忍着关节炎刻出来的
I mean, my dad carved through his arthritis!
可能是因为那只翘起来的腿
Maybe it's the kicky leg.
想想他用一双残手雕刻所投入的时间
I mean, the hours his ruined hands put into this.
他在肥皂中挖掘到了我们
He found us in soap.
今天  米奇尔  我懂得了爱
Today, mitchell, I know love.
我也懂得了"唉"
I no love, either.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
■
翻译：亲爱的小饭  冰蓝  四方虾  王大可  罂粟无果  丁小七
时间轴：浓子   校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
家  庭
摩  登
第五季 第十九集
你四处看看吧
So, take your time looking around.
谢谢
Thanks.
我在帮歌洛莉亚卖掉她在认识杰之前
I'm helping Gloria sell the old apartment
和曼尼住的旧公寓
that she and Manny lived in before she met Jay.
这里的邻居前卫大胆
It's in an up-and-coming neighborhood
拥有鲜明独特的多元文化趋向
with a distinct multicultural bent
正在经历着令人欣喜的城市复兴
that's undergoing an exciting urban renewal.
换个说法就是"基佬们发现了这块宝地"
That's a fancy way of saying "The gays found it."
难以置信我在这里住了五年
I can't believe that I lived here for five years.
连开灯都很痛苦
Even turning the lights on was a pain.
你看
Look at this.
小点声  你个婊子
Keep it down, you bitch!
里维拉太太还活着
Ay. Mrs. Rivera's still alive.
我还真中意这地方
I am really digging this place.
是吧
Right?
瞧瞧这燃气灶  线脚
The gas stove, the moldings --
如今很难找到这样的房子了
they don't make 'em like this anymore.
我可能会全拆掉
I'll probably gut it.
全拆掉
Rip it out.
我也会这么做
That's what I'd do.
我会让我的承包人来看看
I want my contractor to swing by,
但我真的很喜欢这里
but I really like it.
太好了  好极了  谢谢
Great. All right. Thanks.
-拜拜  -再联系
- Bye-bye.  - Talk to you soon.
真高兴认识你
So nice to meet you.
我才不卖给他
I'm not selling to him.
什么  真的吗
What? Really?
他是个不错的买家啊
He's a quality buyer.
你也不想再找租客了
You're tired of finding renters.
这房子是给一大家子人住的
This is a family building.
一大家子几代人
Generations have lived there,
往往是数世同堂
and usually at the same time.
他不过是想转手赚钱
He just wants to flip it.
好吧
Okay.
还有另一个买家大概一小时后能到
I got a backup I can probably get here in an hour.
你想去那里面等吗
You want to wait in there?
你走进去
You walk in that door,
[鸡尾酒吧]
就别想出来了
you never come out.
不不  不是那家酒吧  是那家咖啡厅
No, no, not the bar -- the coffee shop.
对啊  我说的就是那个
Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
但我们可以去隔壁等
But we can wait next door.
那是我以前工作过的美发店
That's my old hair salon where I used to work.
去那里也有的喝
You can get drinks there, too.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
不不不  这不是杰
No, no, no, it's not Jay.
什么这么好笑
What's so funny?
她以为你是我情人
She thinks you're my lover.
太好笑了
That is funny!
我不确定是不是值得一屋子女人捧腹大笑
I don't know if it's "a room full of women laughing" funny,
但是
but...
丽塔  不是啦
Ay, Rita, no.
菲尔是我的一个朋友
Phil is a friend of mine,
我们在等人  过来消磨点时间
and we're just killing time before an appointment.
我也不想这样  歌洛莉亚
I hate to ask, Gloria,
但我新招的店员还没来
but my new girl hasn't shown up.
你可以帮忙吗
Any chance you could help?
当然可以啦
Ay, of course!
一定会很好玩的
It will be so much fun!
我不想毁了我的指甲
I don't want to ruin my nails.
菲尔  你能帮忙洗头吗
Phil, would you do my shampooing?
应该可以吧
Well, I-I guess so.
我们还有时间
We've got the time.
我得声明一下
Just a warning --
大学后我就没有专业洗过头发了
I haven't shampooed professionally since college,
那只是一份兼职  来付拉拉队服装的钱
and that was only part-time to pay for my cheer gear.
我真是太爱炫了
Wow. That was super-braggy.
这里有什么  并排水槽吗
What do we got, double sinks?
花洒还好使吗
What's the nozzle sitch?
我不想太炫耀自己
Not to sound too braggy,
但你妈妈我这周工作
but your mom was kind of
是上天入地无所不能
a badass at work this week.
外公病了  我突然掌管大权
It was hard enough with grandpa being sick
这就已经够艰难了
and me suddenly in charge,
但危机真是一个接一个啊
but it was just one crisis after another.
卢克  亲爱的  我们要走了
Luke, honey, we're going!
仓库起火
Fire in the warehouse,
职业安全和健康署突击检查
surprise inspection from OSHA,
我们最大的顾客企图取消订单
our biggest buyer tried to pull out of a deal,
我得让他打消这个念头
and I have to talk him off a ledge.
随便啦  都结束了
Whatever. It's over now.
我不想说这些来让你们觉得无聊
I don't want to bore you guys with this stuff.
我周三去上班时
So, when I get to work on Wednesday,
玛格利特已经在哭了
Margaret is ready in tears,
接待室里有两名警察
and there are two cops in the waiting room,
我对他们说
and I say to them,
你们最好有人能开18轮巨型货车
"One of you had better be able to drive an 18-wheeler,
因为我要送100块紫檀板去胜利谷
"because I've got 100 rosewood panels to get to Victorville,
不然我就要用薪水补偿了
or it's coming out of my paycheck."
我跟你们说过司机和变质金枪鱼的事了吗
I told you guys about the drivers and the bad tuna?
-变质金枪鱼  -对
- Bad tuna, - Yes.
-说了  -我的确说了
- yeah. - Yes, I did.
妈妈  我都忘记这辆车有多好玩了
Hey, mom, I forgot how fun this car was.
自动门  还有后排的电视
And these automatic doors and that TV in the back.
你知道还有什么很好玩吗
You know what else was fun?
他们周五为我办的派对
The party they threw for me at work on Friday.
那的确有点尴尬啦
I mean, it was a little bit embarrassing.
我都不知道还有"英雌"这个词儿
I didn't even know "She-ro" was a word,
结果他们用糖霜写了这个词
and there it was, in icing.
好啊好啊
Hello, hello!
欢迎来到杰之夜
Welcome to Jay's night.
请报上尊姓大名
Names, please.
确保你在邀请名单内
Want to make sure you're on the list.
开玩笑啦  我很激动
Kidding! Just excited.
吧台上有开胃菜
Appetizers on the bar,
咖啡桌上有拼词游戏
scrabble on the coffee table,
还有我们的特色演讲
and our feature presentation,
"超级大逃亡"
"The Great Escape."
说到这个  海莉
Speaking of which, Haley...
别担心  外公
Don't worry, grandpa.
我不会走的
I'm not leaving.
我今晚没安排
I have no plans for the night.
我也没有
Me, either.
但我没安排是了不得的新闻
But when I say it, it's news.
你说了任何一句完整的话
When you say any complete sentence,
都是了不得的新闻
it's news.
别吵了  姑娘们  爸  你好些了吗
Okay, girls. Dad, you feeling better?
你这周很难受  对吧
You had a rough week, huh?
我没事
Nah. I'm fine.
看来你这周很忙啊
Looks like you had a big week.
你听说了吗
You heard about that?
办公室八卦的所有细节都尽在我掌握
Yeah, I got the blow-by-blow on all the office drama.
顺便说一句  真的...
By the way, sincerely...
什么
Yeah?
超棒...
...great...
吧台那边的鳄梨色拉酱超棒
great guacamole on the bar, there.
就这样吗
Wow. That's it?
你为他做了那么多事
Everything you did for him,
他都不说一句谢谢吗
and he doesn't even say "Thank you"?
我明白了
I get it.
是"英雄"中的"雄"换成了"雌"
It's "Hero" with a "She."
好  我跟上了
Okay, I'm up to speed.
是啊  太冷漠了
Yeah, that was cold.
他就是这样
It's just his way.
多年的失望过后
After years of disappointment,
我学会了不指望我爸给我肯定
I have learned not to expect a pat on the head from my dad.
他做不到
He's not capable of it.
但这教会了我一个很重要的教训
But it has taught me a very important lesson
你们也该学学
that you girls should learn, too --
自我肯定首先要来源于自身
approval comes from within.
我知道  妈妈
I knew that, mom.
你当然知道啦  因为你聪明
'Course you did, 'cause you're smart.
莉莉从浴缸里出来了吗
Hey, is Lily out of the tub?
我们得赶去我爸家了
We got to be at my dad's soon.
不
Oh, no!
没什么大不了的
It's not that big of a deal.
我们可以稍微迟到一会儿
We can be a little late.
不  莉莉把我们的蛋糕人偶
No! Lily had the cake topper
带进浴缸了
in the tub with her!
不  怎么会犯这么严重的错误呢
Oh, no. How could such a terrible mistake have occurred?
我想她一定以为那是个玩具之类的
I think she must have just thought it was a toy or something.
希望人偶没有被玩坏
Well, I hope it's not completely ruined forever.
没有  你开玩笑吧
Oh, no. Are you kidding me?
我爸爸用了特殊的虫胶清漆
My daddy uses a special shellac on this thing.
这玩意儿能防水
This is water-resistant,
隔热  百毒不侵
heat-resistant -- you name it.
真好
Good to know.
是啊  放在安全的地方
Yeah, but put it someplace safe.
可能还有点滑
It could still be slippery,
小心点
so be careful.
是吗
Is it?
是啊  的确是
Oh, yeah, it is!
好滑
It's slippery!
没坏吧
Is it okay?
安然无恙
Not a scratch.
显然我比看上去要强壮
Apparently, I'm tougher than I look.
孩子们  玩得开心吗
Hey, boys. Having fun?
你知道的
You know it.
我们喜欢杰之夜
Love us some Jay's night.
好了  我们走吧
Okay, we're out of here.
克里斯蒂・休斯
Kristy Hughes,
外号"克里斯蒂・胸器"
A.K.A. "Kristy huge ones,"
在两个街区外开泳池派对
is having a pool party two blocks away.
那杰怎么办
What about Jay?
他认为我们就是在开派对
He thinks we're at a party.
他不会知道的
He'll never know.
我们偷偷溜出去  溜进屋里
We sneak out, work the room,
欣赏大胸
cannonball, cannonball,
然后我们赶回来吃晚餐
and we're back in time for dinner.
你被邀请了吗
Were you even invited?
没有
No.
但那只是因为我不认识她或她的朋友
But that's only because I don't know her or any of her friends.
非法入侵的事咱们不能干
We're not invading her house.
再说  我这头发在泳池派对上
Besides, this hair at a pool party --
一碰水就跟安全气囊似的爆开了
One dunk, and it goes off like an airbag.
这是什么  你做了酱汁吗
What's this? You made sauce?
你生病了
Well, you were sick.
我不知道你能不能坚持做饭
I didn't know if you could handle it.
越战的时候我得了肝炎
Back in Vietnam, I had hepatitis.
照样给三百个士兵准备了
Still managed to cook Thanksgiving dinner
感恩节晚餐
for 300 soldiers.
我觉得我能搞得定酱汁
I think I can handle sauce.
我这不是帮你省了麻烦嘛
Well, I saved you the trouble.
玛格利特告诉我公司在用新的运货卡车
So, Margaret tells me I'm using some new delivery trucks now.
是的  它们都是混合动力的
Yeah. They're hybrid.
确实贵一些
Now, they cost a little more,
但是我把使用绿色产品的
but when I factored in the tax rebates
退税算上
you get for going green,
我们就把钱赚回来了
we come out ahead.
提到绿色
Speaking of "Green,"
你蔬菜放得太多了吧
you went a little heavy on the vegetables, huh?
我不确定我能吃下任何健康食物
I'm not sure I can stomach anything that's healthy.
天啊  妈妈  那些卡车听起来真不错
Gosh, mom, that truck thing sounds so amazing.
是啊
Yeah!
没关系  爸
It's fine, dad.
只做力所能及的  对吧
Only do what we're capable of, right?
该死
Oh, damn.
不  斯黛拉  站住  不行
No, Stella, stay. No.
乖狗狗
Good girl.
谢谢  斯黛拉
Thank you, Stella.
谢谢你听我的话
Thank you for listening.
我太为你骄傲了
Oh, I'm so proud of you.
谁是我的好闺女
Who's my best girl?
不用了
Don't.
好了姑娘们  我们准备好拼字游戏了
Okay, girls, we are ready for scrabble.
我去拿些零食
I'll grab some snacks.
我要薯片  拜托了
Uh, potato chips, please.
然后我就能整晚听你抱怨
Oh, so I can hear about how much
你有多讨厌自己了
you hate yourself all night?
你好  卢克
Hello, Luke.
拜托  我们去吧
Come on! We've got to go!
那个派对上都是高二的学生
That party's full of sophomores.
那些学姐们可都是过来人
Those women have lived.
不  我们现在回屋去
No, we're going back inside,
吃杰准备的食物
we're eating Jay's food,
然后玩他的桌游
and we're playing his board games.
应该叫"无聊"游戏吧
More like boring games.
那名字本身就和"无聊"读音相同
They're already called "Board."
你没必要再做多余演绎了
You don't make it more clever by --
算了
Never mind.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
你和婚礼主唱把问题都解决了吗
Did you work everything out with the wedding singer?
是的  我刚放弃了我的压轴表演
Oh, yeah -- I'm just dropping my big finale
因为他要唱同一首歌
because he's doing the same song.
《我的路》吗
"My Way"?
已经是他的路了
His way.
大家好啊
Hey, guys.
抱歉我们迟到了
Sorry we're late,
但我们带了红酒
but we come with wine.
还有雕刻艺术哦
And whittlin'!
看看
Check it out.
这是我父亲做的美丽礼物
This is a beautiful gift my father made
为了放在结婚蛋糕上面的
for the top of our wedding cake.
我猜他肥皂用光了所以没把我放进去
I guess he ran out of soap before he got to me.
-太糟了  -给你
- Darn. - For you.
女士们  来看看
Ladies, check out
肥皂版的米奇尔和小卡叔叔
your uncle Mitch and Cam in soap.
那是肥皂做的吗
That's soap?
太漂亮了
It's beautiful.
这是我最恐怖的噩梦
This is my worst nightmare.
你不应该把否决权都浪费了的
You shouldn't have blown through those vetoes.
这就是小卡爸爸眼里的我
This is how Cam's dad sees me --
像个谄媚的黄花闺女一样
like some fawning damsel.
小卡更像个黄花闺女
If anything, Cam's the damsel.
爸
Dad!
谢谢
Thank you.
大婚之前什么都可能发生
A lot can happen before the big day.
相信我  我什么招都试过了
Believe me, I've already tried.
那东西简直坚不可摧
That thing is indestructible.
如果它消失不见了呢
What if it went missing?
我这里可总是丢东西
Things disappear around here all the time.
是吗
Do they?
一直都是
All the time.
我有个小伙伴
Let's just say I have a friend
总在这样的时刻帮我
who helps me in these kinds of situations.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
你知道的越少越好
The less you know, the better.
那我不听了
I'm not listening.
这段对话从没发生过
We never had this conversation.
这是段"没话"
This is a non-versation.
是的
Right.
我要你  "不动手"
I am giving you the...no-ahead.
我太想念你们了
Oh, I miss you girls.
我的白人家庭里没人觉得我幽默
Nobody in my white family thinks that I am funny.
亲  赫克托遇到你前有自己的人生
Honey, Hector had a life before he met you.
所以我就得和他前任一起吃饭吗
So I have to eat dinner with his ex?
那你肯定不想让他自己去吧
Well, you certainly don't want him going alone --
特别是他还有那么段历史
Not with his history.
你到底是生谁的气呢
Who are you really mad at?
我不知道
Ay, I don't know.
说说吧  路易莎
Come on, Luisa.
劳尔
Raul!
赫克托会像劳尔那样伤我的心
Hector's going to hurt me just like Raul did!
这就是了
There it is.
但赫克托不是劳尔  对吗
But Hector isn't raul, okay?
他们只是表亲而已
They're just cousins.
我们得走了
We need to get a move on.
客户会在四点来看房
The client's gonna come over to the apartment at 4:00.
我太忙了  脱不开身
I am swamped. I can't just leave.
歌洛莉亚  我们是来这卖你的公寓的
Gloria, we're here to sell your apartment.
不是来发廊打工的
We don't work at the salon.
非常感谢  比安卡
Muchísimas gracias, Bianca.
别再跟那个男人发短信了
No más texting ese hombre.
这是一对快生小孩的年轻夫妇
It's for a young couple with a baby on the way.
买房不是为了转手赚钱
They're not flippers.
他们是想找个地方安定下来
They're looking for a place to settle down and make a home.
跟他们换个时间
Okay, just move them.
要是他们真想要这房子肯定会回来的
If they really want it, they'll come back.
可是  歌洛莉亚
But, Gloria --
拜托你帮我处理一下安娜的锡纸
Ay, please, just help me with Anna's foils.
我得赶紧去帮人驳发
I have a weave emergency!
有点不对劲
Something's not right.
什么  怎么了
Qué qué pasó?
不  不  跟你没关系  你好着呢
No, no, no, not with you. You look great.
你知道谁会痛恨这个造型吗
You know who's gonna hate this,
对你羡慕嫉妒恨的小姐妹
is a certain jealous sister.
来  我们击个掌
Cinco de my, oh, my.
我这儿有这么多个"I"让我怎么玩
How am I supposed to do this with so many "I"s on my rack?
[曼尼听成"eyes on my rack: 这么多只眼睛盯着我的脖子"]
真抱歉
Sorry.
卢克在哪儿
Where's Luke?
他拿个字典要这么久吗
How long does it take him to get the dictionary?
我们很清楚地告诉他字典长什么样子了
We described it for him perfectly.
等等
Wait a minute.
他不会是不回来了吧
He's not coming back.
[音似Move your ass: 动作快点]
移动你的"S"
Ugh. Move your "S."
我已经走得够快了
I-I'm going as fast as I can.
米奇尔  它不见了
Mitchell! It's gone!
什么东西
What is?
那个蛋糕装饰人偶
The cake topper.
莉莉  你有看到之前跟你一起洗澡的
Lily, have you seen the little daddies
小版爸爸们吗
you were bathing with earlier?
别这么说话
Don't say that.
我看到斯黛拉在玩它
I saw Stella playing with it.
什么
What?
瞧瞧她身上  全是泥巴
Oh, look at her. She's all muddy.
她肯定是叼出去埋起来了
She must have brought it outside and buried it.
她老是做这种事
She does it all the time!
不  我们必须找到它
Oh, no. We have to go find it.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
那东西估计是找不到了
That thing's as good as gone.
真糟糕
Dang it!
最惨的是
And the worst part is,
我们连张照片都没来得及拍
we don't even have a picture of it.
我们有吗
Do we?
我们不能放弃
Okay, we can't give up.
我们去院子里找找看
Let's go out into the yard and look for it.
注意点  换成我是不会干涉斯黛拉
Careful. I wouldn't come between Stella
藏任何东西的
and anything she's buried.
她有自己的天性
She's a wild animal.
不会别人告诉她会做什么
No telling what she'll do.
这姿势真是充满挑衅的味道
That's a very aggressive stance.
卢克  等等
Luke! Wait!
瞧瞧你
Oh. Look at that.
你都离开院子了
You left your yard,
你的电子项圈居然没有响
and your little shock collar didn't go off.
卢克
Luke --
好了  新计划是这样的
Okay, so, here's the new plan.
你站后面  由我先来活跃气氛
You hang back while I break the ice,
等到一个恰当的时候
and then, when the time is right --
曼尼  你来了
Manny! You made it!
这是谁
Who's this?
"Who's this?"
拜托
Excuse me,
克里斯蒂・胸器  我是有名字的
Kristy huge ones, I have a name.
好了  别闹了
Okay, come on. Stop.
我追了你一整天已经受够了
I'm tired of chasing you all day.
那就别追我
Then don't.
去那个无聊的派对上玩吧
Stay as long as you want at that lame party.
你想聊聊吗
You want to talk?
你才应该是那个呆呆的配角  不是我
You're the dorky sidekick, not me.
能稍微友好点吗
Want to talk nicer?
凭什么她请你不请我
How could you be invited and I wasn't?
我不知道
I don't know.
貌似过去我身上让人觉得奇怪的地方
It's like the stuff that used to make me kind of weird,
开始招人喜欢了
people are starting to like.
所以呢
So?
我还跟以前一样
I'm the same as I always was.
说不定你可以提高一下自己
Well...maybe you could upgrade a little.
[尤达:《星球大战》中的人物]
我们受够了你的"尤达"音
Uh, we're tired of the yoda voice,
如果有个女孩告诉你她去了伦敦
and if a girl tells you she went to london,
最好别问她是不是看见了法国
maybe don't ask if she also saw France.
我还是喜欢
I liked things better when you were the one
你比较像鸵鸟的时候
who was ostrich-sized.
什么
What?
你懂的  一个怪异的圈外人
You know, like a freaky outsider --
鹤立鸡群的感觉
the way an ostrich feels around regular birds.
你知道女孩子还喜欢什么吗
You know what else girls like?
神秘又安静的类型
The mysterious, silent type.
你在对我的酱汁做什么  伙计
What are you doing with my sauce, there, cookie?
那才是你的
That's yours.
这是我的
This is mine.
我早上就准备好了
I prepped it this morning.
我想了下  为什么不做呢
I figured, why not make it?
因为我已经做好了
Um...maybe because I already made sauce?
多多益善
Can't have too much.
是吗
Can't ya?
把汤勺递给我
Hand me that ladle, huh?
你干嘛  我已经拿住了
What are you doing? I got it.
你要说什么
What do you say?
什么
What?
当别人为你做事的时候你要说什么
What do you say when somebody does something for you?
你要说什么
What do you say?
你想让我谢谢你把汤勺给我吗
You want me to thank you for handing me a ladle?
你感谢了狗狗站着不动
You thanked the dog for staying --
虽然它其实什么都没做
which is basically doing nothing --
所以我确定你知道该怎么说
so I know you know the words.
好吧
Fine.
谢谢你把汤勺递给我
Thank you for handling me the ladle.
你确定这些煮好了吗
You sure those are ready?
[旧时通过意大利面是否能粘到墙上来判断是否煮熟]
你还没往墙上扔呢
You didn't throw one against the wall.
爸  现在没有人这么做了
Oh, dad, nobody does that anymore.
就是说我们做所有事都换新方法了是吧
Oh. I guess we have new ways for doing everything now, huh?
不  我可没那么说
No. I didn't say that.
我只是说你可以直接尝一下熟了没有
I'm just saying that you can taste your food
而不是像黑猩猩一样往墙上甩
instead of flinging it at the wall like a chimp.
好吧
Okay.
味道如何
How's it taste?
事实上  还不错
Actually, mm, that's pretty good.
但是如果能加点
But it could use a little,
酱料
um...sauce.
我来试试  好烫
Let me just -- ooh, hot.
再加点帕尔马干酪
Try a little Parmesan with that?
我应该把面包放进烤箱了
I should probably get that bread in the oven.
只要
Just...
好了  好了
Okay! Hey!
这里交给我们吧
Hey, how about we take over in here
你们去收拾一下准备吃饭了
while you two get cleaned up for dinner?
好主意
Yes, good idea.
好的
Yeah. Okay.
自我肯定首先要来源于自身
Approval comes from within.
谢谢
Thank you.
你的酱料需要加点蒜
Your sauce needs garlic.
-好了  -好了
- Okay.   - Okay.
这是个表
And that's a clock.
好吧  再试另一个地方
Okay, well, do another one.
我试了四个了
I've done like four.
这只狗比你叔叔克莱顿还爱囤东西
This dog is a worse hoarder than your uncle Clayton.
他是个收藏家
He's a collector.
收藏过期酸奶吗
Of expired yogurt?
累死我了
Getting tired.
小卡  能不能别找了
Cam, can we just stop, please?
我觉得我们已经尽力了
I feel like we've done our best,
肯定是找不到了
but we're just not gonna find it.
找到了
Found it!
太好了
Oh! Good.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
我还没告诉你我对它的宏伟计划呢
I hadn't even told you my biggest plan for this yet.
比装饰蛋糕还宏伟的计划吗
Bigger than the top of our wedding cake?
我要用它做个模子然后批量生产
I'm gonna have a mold made of it and give a reproduction
赠送给每一位来参加婚礼的
to everyone who comes to the wedding
和来不了的客人
and everyone who can't come to the wedding.
想象一下数百个我们的人偶散布全国
Imagine hundreds of these across the country.
不
No!
不行  不行  绝对不行
No! No! Absolutely not!
我讨厌它  太恶心了
I hate it! It's awful!
我就知道
I knew it!
它只是恰巧出现在莉莉的浴缸里
It just shows up in Lily's bath,
然后突然间  又被狗叼走了吗
and then, all of a sudden, the dog has it?
你就是故意盯着它不放
You have it in for this beautiful topper.
你看看  你好好看看它
Look at this. Look at it. Look at it!
你一副威风凛凛大块头的样子
Come on, you're all heroic and Paul Bunyan-y,
我呢  我就像个娘娘腔
and I'm -- I'm, like, some sissy man
红着脸颊  夹着腿
with -- with pinkish cheeks and a turned-out heel.
那只是一种表现形式
It's a caricature.
重要的是它代表的意义
What matters is what it represents.
我爸爸为我们亲手制作的
My daddy making this for us
说明他已经接受了我们本来的样子
means he's accepted us for who we are!
你难道不明白吗
Don't you get that?
我倒是没有从这个角度想过
I never really thought about it that way.
你确实没有
No. You hadn't.
我只是有些敏感了
I'm just being sensitive.
我应该神经再大条一点
I need to have a thicker skin.
我真的非常非常抱歉
I-I'm really, really sorry.
不  不用抱歉
No, don't -- don't -- don't be sorry.
不用
No.
我不希望有你不喜欢的东西
And I -- n-- I don't want something at the wedding
出现在婚礼上
that makes you uncomfortable.
不  那不太公平
Well, no, that doesn't seem fair.
我的否决权已经用光了
I've used up all my vetoes.
如果
Well, if it --
能让你好受一些的话
I guess, if it makes you feel better,
我可以再给你加一个否决权
I could give you one more veto --
但你也要给我加一个
if you give me one more, too.
好吧  当然可以
Okay, sure.
如果以后
And in the future,
有什么事情
if there's anything --
辞掉婚礼歌手
The wedding singer.
好的  谢谢  爸爸
Okay. Thanks, daddy.
我会给你一张非常适合的照片作参考
I'll send you the perfect picture to model it on.
今天过后我相信了
After today, I'm convinced
10%的填埋垃圾是头发
our landfills are 10% hair.
是啊
Oh, yes.
我都忘记这事这么累人了
I forgot how exhausting this is.
现在我们只需要
Well, all we have to do
回公寓去见一下客户
is meet the clients back at the apartment,
然后就可以回家了
and then we can head home.
不  我现在好累
Ay, no. I'm too tired now.
改期吧
Let's reschedule.
真的吗  还改
Really? Again?
是啊  下周再见吧
Yes. Let's meet them next week.
而且  杰的聚会我们已经迟到了
And besides, we're late for Jay's party.
我不会让你这个样子回家的
Well, I'm not letting you go home looking like this.
你头发后面有点乱
You're a little ratty back here.
是啊
Ay, no.
没事  没事  我来
No, no, no. I got it.
你放松就好
You just relax.
今天真是够累的
What a day, huh?
回到这里一定唤起了你很多回忆
Being back here must bring up a lot of memories.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
也许还有一些情绪
Maybe even some emotions.
是啊  感觉怪怪的
Yeah. It feels weird.
怪是一个形容词
No, weird's an adjective,
不是一种情绪  但你继续说
not an emotion, but go on.
我现在的生活与以前大不相同
Well, it's just that my life now is so different than before --
轻松多了
so much easier.
所以你觉得
And that makes you feel...?
很好
Good.
还有呢
And also...?
也不好
And bad.
为什么
Why?
我也不知道
I don't know.
说说吧  歌洛莉亚
Come on, now, Gloria.
我也不知道
I don't know.
我想我只是觉得有些惭愧
I guess it just makes me feel a little ashamed.
为什么会惭愧呢
Now, what in the world do you have to be ashamed of?
只是  你懂的
It's just that, you know,
以前住在这里时
before, when I used to live here,
我要努力工作赚钱
I used to work for every penny.
我全靠自己
I would stand on my own two feet.
现在我穿着这些昂贵的鞋子
Now I just stand on expensive shoes
都是杰买给我的
that Jay buys for me.
是因为这样才不想卖掉房子吗
Is that why it's so hard to let go of the apartment?
不  菲尔  不是因为这个
No, Phil, it's not that --
歌洛莉亚
Gloria.
也许是吧
Maybe.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria.
是的
Yes.
它是最后一件属于原来的我的东西
It's the last piece of the old me.
停  停  你太用力了
No, no! You're going too deep!
抱歉抱歉
Oh. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起  但我觉得你的想法不对
I'm sorry, but I think you're looking at this all wrong.
原来的你还在这里
The old you hasn't gone anywhere.
看你培养曼尼和乔的方式
I-I-I see it in the way you're raising Manny and Joe,
看你照顾杰的样子
the way you care for Jay.
你从没把任何东西当作理所当然
You never take anyone or anything for granted.
你多年来一直努力工作
You worked hard for years
那时你也不知道生活会不会变好
without knowing that things were gonna get better.
然后你得到了回报
And then the universe rewarded you.
这没什么好惭愧的
There's nothing to be ashamed of.
你不会因为
So you're not mad at me
我不想卖房子而生气吧
because I don't want to sell the apartment?
不会
No.
有一天你会准备好的
You'll know when you're ready,
我等你
and I'll be here.
菲尔
Aw, Phil.
你最好了
You're the best.
没有谁像你这样
There's no one like you.
克莱尔  看起来真好吃
Claire, that looks so good.
我等不及要尝尝了
I can't wait to try it.
谢谢
Thank you.
有什么地方不太对劲
Something has happened here.
你们一定很高兴
Well, you'll all be happy to know
我们为了找到蛋糕装饰人偶
that our search for the cake topper
挖出了好多家族宝贝
unearthed a number of family treasures.
拜托  小卡  我们这正吃饭呢
Come on, Cam. We're eating over here.
等一下
Wait.
这不是父亲节我送给你的吗
Didn't I give you this for Father's Day?
还有这个
And that.
看到这狗的本性了吧
You see how this dog is?
我的卡拉OK麦克风
My karaoke microphone.
杰  快看
Jay, check it out!
是另一个无线通话机
The other walkie-talkie!
真替你脸红  杰・普里契特
Shame on you, Jay Pritchett!
你利用这只狗把你讨厌的东西都埋了
You have used this dog to bury the things that you hate.
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yeah!
你从何时开始需要别人帮你埋东西了
Since when do you need help burying things?
淡定  她也埋了我的东西  看
Calm down. She buries stuff of mine, too. Look.
上个月办公室的人给我买了这只钟
Everybody at the office bought me this clock last month.
宝贝  你是怎么回事
Honey, what's the matter with you?
这个问题该问你吧
That's a question that maybe you should answer.
天呐  我的耳机
Oh, my gosh! My headphones!
这太恶劣了
That's the worst.
谨以此庆祝从业40周年
"Here's to 40 years in the business.
享受你的新家伙吧  老家伙
Enjoy your new timer, old-timer."
我猛然间明白了
Suddenly, it made sense.
在我爸爸眼里
In my dad's mind,
我要接住火炬了  而他还不想传下去
I was reaching for a torch he wasn't ready to pass.
确实有朝一日
Sure, someday,
我会接手他的生意
I'm gonna take over his business,
但不是今晚
but not tonight.
今晚还是属于杰的
Tonight is still Jay's night.
爸爸
So, dad...
其实
turns out,
我上周有很多问题想问你
I did have a bunch of questions for you last week,
但我不想打扰你
but I didn't want to bother you with them.
我不想让你觉得我搞不定
I didn't want you to think I couldn't handle it.
寻求帮助没有什么可耻的
There's no shame in asking for help.
你可以随时打给我
You can always call.
我不用打给你
Well, I won't need to.
你会一直在走廊尽头的办公室里不是吗
You'll be in the office down the hall, right?
没错
Right.
金发姑娘呼叫熊爸爸
Goldilocks to Papa Bear.
请回答  熊爸爸
Come in, Papa Bear.
我是熊爸爸
This is Papa Bear.
位置在车库  熊爸爸
On location in the garage, Papa Bear.
这里有标着你名字的热可可
Got some cocoa with your name on it.
你在什么方位
What's your 20?
不是吧
Oh, what the hell?
怎么了
What's going on?
孩子们又和我解除好友关系了
The kids unfriended me again.
这要我如何打探他们在干什么呢
How am I supposed to know what's going on in their lives
他们也不跟我说
If they never talk to me?
亲爱的
Honey...
让我来
I got this.
是啊  今年过得不太顺
Yeah. It's been kind of a rough year.
新的学校
New school,
新的小伙伴
new kids,
如今我把妹都要听一个
and now I'm taking advice about girls
有自己的擦皮鞋机的孩子的建议
from a kid who has his own shoe buffer.
什么
What?!
我喝了啤酒
I tried beer.
爸爸  这感觉真棒
Wow, dad. This feels great.
很好  很好
Good. Good.
你真的
You're-- you sure there's --
没什么心事吗
there's nothing on your mind?
没有
No.
怎么这么问  爸爸
Why do you ask, dad?
你看起来有点心烦
You seem upset about something.
只是  人到了一定年纪
It's just, you reach a certain age,
就开始怀疑
and you start to wonder,
我成为自己想成为的人了吗
"Am I everything I wanted to be?"
我是在卖房子
I mean, am I selling houses,
还是只是在卖而已
or am I just selling out?
还有呢
Anything else?
艾丽克斯喝啤酒了
Alex tried beer.